[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
So far we've discussed how to regularize logistic regression.
حتى الآن لقد ناقشنا كيفية تنظيم الانحدار اللوجستي.
We briefly mentioned what happens when you we have L1 regularized
ذكرنا بإيجاز ما يحدث يكون لدينا انحدار
logistic regression.
لوجستي منظم بواسطة L1.
Let's talk about it in a little bit more detail.
لنتحدث عن ذلك بمزيد من التفصيل قليلًا.
Unlike in a regression course,
على العكس من الدورة التدريبية الخاصة بالانحدار.
we're not going to derive the learning algorithm for L1 regularize with
لن نشتق خوارزمية التعلم لتنظيم L1
the sync regression can be the similar thing to what you did with lasso.
مع انحدار المزامنة، سيكون الأمر مشابهًا لما قمت به مع lasso.
We're just going to show kind of the impact it has on our data.
نحن سنقوم فقط بعرض نوع التأثير الذي يحدثه على بياناتنا.
On our learn models.
على نماذج التعلم الخاصة بنا.
So recall the notion of sparsity.
لذا، تذكر مفهوم التضاؤل.
So a model sparse when many of those wj's are equal to zero and that can help us
وبالتالي يتضاءل النموذج عندما يساوي العديد من قيم wj صفر ويمكن أن يساعدنا هذا
with both efficiency and interpretability of the models as we saw in regression.
من حيث كل من الفعالية وقابلية تفسير النماذج كما رأينا في الانحدار.
So for example, let's say that we have a lot of data and a lot of features so
إذن، على سبيل المثال، لنفترض أن لدينا الكثير من البيانات، والعديد من الميزات بحيث
the number of w's that you have can be a 100 billion, 100 billion possible values.
يمكن أن يكون عدد قيم w التي لديك 100 مليار، 100 مليار قيمة محتملة.
Things can in practice in all sorts of settings.
يمكن أن تحدث أمور أثناء الممارسة بجميع أنواع الإعدادات.
For example, many of the spam filters out there have hundreds of billions of
فعلى سبيل المثال، لدى العديد من عوامل تصفية البريد العشوائي مئات المليارات
parameters in them, or coefficients they learn from data.
من المتغيرات فيها، أو المعاملات التي تتعلمها من البيانات.
So this has a couple problems.
حسنًا، يوجد بهذا بعض من المشكلات.
It can be expensive to make a prediction.
يمكن أن يكون إجراء توقع أمرًا مكلفًا.
You have to go through 100 billion values.
حيث يجب أن تمر على 100 مليار قيمة.
However if I have a sparse solution where many of these
مع ذلك إذا كان لدى حل تضاؤل حيث يكون العديد من قيم
w's are actually equal to zero then when I'm trying to make a prediction.
w هذه مساويًا لصفر بالفعل، فعندئذ أنا أحاول إجراء توقع.
So I'm judging will be at the sine of wj times the feature hj of xi.
لذا أحكم أنه سيكون عند جيب wj ضرب الخاصية hj لـ xi.
I only have to look at no zero quotations wj.
يتعين علي فقط النظر إلى اقتباسات wj التي لا تساوي صفرًا.
Everything else can be ignored.
يمكن تجاهل أي شيء آخر.
So if I have a 100 billion coefficients but only say 100,000 of those are non zero
وهكذا إذا كان لدي 100 مليار معامل ولكن لنقول 100000 فقط من هذه المعاملات لا يساوي صفرًا
then it's going to be much faster to make a prediction.
فعندئذ سيكون من عملية إجراء توقع
This makes a huge difference in practice.
فهذا يُحدث فارقًا هائلًا أثناء الممارسة.
The other impact that sparsity has having many zero coefficients being zero
التأثير الآخر للتضاؤل هو الحصول على العديد من العوامل المساوية لصفر
is that it can help you interpret the non zero coefficients.
حيث كونها مساوية لصفر يمكن أن يساعدك في تفسير المعاملات غير المساوية لصفر.
So you can look at the small number of non zero coefficients and
لذا، يمكنك النظر إلى العدد الصغير للمعاملات غير المساوية لصفر
try to make an interpretation, this is why a prediction gets made.
ومحاولة إجراء تفسير، وهذا هو سبب إجراء توقع.
Such interpretations can be used for practice in many ways, so
يمكن استخدام مثل هذه التفسيرات للتدرب بعدة طرق،
how you learn logistic regression classifier with sparsity in that,
لذا الطريقة التي تتعلم بها مصنف الانحدار اللوجستي مع التضاؤل
sparsity inducing penalty.
عقوبة تحث على التضاؤل.
So what you do is take the same log-likelihood function Lw but
حسنًا، ما تجريه هو أن تأخذ نفس دالة لوغاريتم الاحتمال Lw لكن
we add extra L1 penalty.
نضيف عقوبة L1 إضافية.
Which is the sum of the absolute value of w0,
وهي مجموع القيمة المطلقة لـ w0
the absolute value of w1 all the way to the absolute value wd.
والقيمة المطلقة لـ w1 وصولًا حتى القيمة المطلة لـ wd.
So by just changing the squares,
وهكذا بمجرد تغيير القيم الأسية،
sum of squares to be sum of absolute values we go into what's called L1
مجموع القيم الأسية إلى مجموع القيم المطلقة نحن ننتقل إلى ما يُدعى الانحدار
regularized logistic regression which gives you sparse solutions.
اللوجستي المنظم L1 الذي يمنحك حلولاً متضائلة.
So that small change leads to sparse solutions.
بحيث يؤدي التغيير البسيط إلى حلول متضائلة.
So just like we did with L2 regularization.
وهكذا تمامًا مثل الذي أجريناه مع التنظيم L2.
Here, we're also going to have a parameter
يكون لدينا هنا كذلك متغير
lander which controls how much regularization we introduce.
الهبوط، الذي يتحكم في مقدار التنظيم الذي نجريه.
So how much penalty we're going to introduce.
وبالتالي مقدار العقوبة التي سنقدمها.
And objective becomes the log-likelihood of the data,
ويصبح الهدف لوغاريتم الاحتمال الخاص بالبيانات،
minus lambda times the sum of these absolute values, the L1 penalty.
ناقص λ ضرب مجموع هذه القيم المطلقة، عقوبة L1.
When lambda equals to 0, we have no regularization,
عندما تكون λ تساوي 0، لا يكون لدينا تنظيم،
which leads us to the standard MLE
مما يقودنا إلى حل MLE
solution.
القياسي.
Just like we had in the case of L2 regularization.
تمامًا كما كان لدينا في حالة التنظيم L2.
Now when lambda is equal to infinity,
الآن عندما تكون λ مساوية لمقدار لا نهائي،
we have only penalty so
يكون لدينا العقوبة فقط لذلك
all weight is on regularization.
يكون كل الترجيح على التنظيم.
And that's going to lead to w hat being everything 0, all 0 coefficients.
وسيؤدي هذا إلى أن تصبح كل قيم w hat مساوية 0، جميع معاملات 0.
Now the case that we really care about was on lambda similar between 0 and
والآن الحالة التي تهمنا حقًا هي عندنا تكون λ مساوية لقيمة ما بين 0
infinity which leads to what are called Sparse Solutions.
ومقدار لا نهائي مما يؤدي إلى ما يُطلق عليه الحلول المتضائلة.
Where some wj's are now going to be equal to 0 but
حيث ستصبح بعض من قيم wj الآن مساوية لصفر ولكن
hopefully, many other wj's and
لنأمل أن العديد من قيم wj الأخرى
this is the maximum wj hats are going to be exactly 0.
وهذا هو الحد الأقصى لقيم wj hats سيكون 0 بالضبط.
So that's what we're going to try to aim for.
لذلك هذا ما سنحاول أن نصل إليه.
So let's revisit those coefficient paths, and
حسنًا، لنعيد دراسة مسارات المعاملات تلك
here I'm showing you coefficient paths of L2 penalty.
وأنا أوضح لك هنا مسارات معاملات عقوبة L2.
You see that when the lambda parameter's low, you have large coefficients learned,
يمكنك أن ترى أنه عندما يكون متغير λ منخفضًا، يتم استخلاص معامل كبير
and when the lambda parameters gets larger, you got smaller coefficients.
وعندما يصبح متغير λ أكبر تحصل على معاملات أصغر.
So, they go from large to small, but they're never exactly 0.
وهكذا، هي تتحول من كبيرة إلى صغيرة ولكن لا تساوي 0 بالضبط.
So, the coefficients never become exactly 0.
لذلك لا تصبح المعاملات مساوية لصفر بالضبط أبدًا.
If you look however at the coefficient paths when the regularization is L1,
إذا نظرت مع ذلك إلى مسارات المعاملات عندما يكون التنظيم L1،
well guess if would be much more interesting.
حسنًا أعتقد سيكون الأمر مثيرًا للاهتمام أكثر.
So, for example, in the beginning,
إذن، على سبيل المثال، في البداية
the coefficient of the smiley face oops that should be frowny.
يكون لمعامل الوجه المبتسم عفوًا يتعين أن يكون هذا عابسًا.
That should be smiley face has a large positive value.
يتعين أن يكون هذا وجهًا مبتسمًا قيمة موجبة كبيرة.
But eventually becomes exactly zero from here on.
ولكن في نهاية المطاف، يصبح مساويًا لصفر بالضبط من الآن فصاعدًا.
And similarly, the coefficient for the frowney face
وبالمثل، يكون معامل الوجه العابس
is a large negative value, but eventually over here the frowney face
قيمة كبيرة سالبة، ولكن في نهاية المطاف هنا يكون لمعامل الوجه العابس
has a coefficient that becomes 0.
معامل يصبح مساويًا لصفر.
And so it goes from large all the way to exactly zero.
وهكذا يتجه الأمر من كبير وصولًا إلى صفر بالضبط.
And we see that for many of the other words.
ونلاحظ ذلك للعديد من الكلمات الأخرى.
For example in the beginning the coefficient of the word hate is pretty
على سبيل المثال في البداية، يكون معامل كلمة hate (الكره) مرتفعًا
high and that's a pretty important word but around here hate becomes irrelevant.
للغاية وهذه كلمة مهمة للغاية ولكن هنا لا تصبح الكلمة ذات صلة.
And so as just a quick reminder, these are product reviews and trying to
حسنًا، كتذكير سريع فقط، هذه هي مراجعات خاصة بمنتجات
figure out whether it's a positive or negative review for the product.
ونحاول معرفة ما إذا كانت مراجعة إيجابية أم سلبية للمنتج.
And work with, we can look at what coefficient stays non zero for
والعمل مع، يمكننا النظر إلى المعامل الذي يظل غير مساوي لصفر
the longest time.
لأطول وقت.
And this is exactly this line over here, where it never hits 0,
وهذا بالضبط، هذا الخط هنا، حيث لا تساوي القيمة 0 أبدًا،
never stays exactly 0.
ولا تظل مساوية لصفر بالضبط.
And this is a co-efficient of the word disappointed.
وهذا هو معامل الكلمة disappointed (خائب الأمل).
So, you might be disappointed to learn that frowny face is
لذا قد تصاب بخيبة الأمل لمعرفة أن ليست قيمة الوجه العابس
not the one that becomes 0.
هي التي تصبح مساوية لصفر.
But in the beginning, disappoint is not as,
ولكن في البداية، لا تكون خيبة الأمل مثل
the coefficient is not as large, not as significant as a frowny face but
أن المعامل ليس كبيرًا مثل، الوجه العابس ولكن
it's the one that stays negative for the longest.
هي التي تظل قيمة سالبة لأطول فترة.
And so frowny face is not, you might be disappointed
وهكذا، لا يكون الوجه العابس كذلك
to know that friendly face is not as important as disappointed.
فقد تصاب بخيبة الأمل لمعرفة أن الوجه الودود ليس بأهمية كلمة "خائب الأمل"
[LAUGH] And disappointed probably because it's prevalent in more reviews and
[ضحك] وكلمة "خائب الأمل" ربما لأنها منتشرة في مراجعات أكثر
when you say disappointed you're really like in a negative review.
وعندما تقول "خائب الأمل" فأنت بالفعل كما لو كنت في مراجعة سلبية.
That coefficient goes on for a long time.
يستمر هذا المعامل لوقت طويل.
So you see these transitions.
لذا ترى هذه التحولات.
So the coefficients of those small numbers like reviews goes to zero.
وبالتالي، يتحول معامل مراجعات الإعجاب ذات الأعداد الصغيرة إلى صفر.
Earlier on, the smiley face will last for a while then it becomes zero.
في وقت سابق، دام الوجه المبتسم لبعض من الوقت ثم أصبح مساويًا لصفر.
Frowny face lasts for longer and then it becomes exactly zero.
ودام الوجه العابس لوقت أطول ثم أصبح مساويًا لصفر.
But propositionally large lambdas, all those are zero except for
ولكن بشكل مقترح قيم λ الكبير، تكون جميعها مساوية لصفر ما عدا
the coefficient at this point.
المعامل "خائب الأمل".
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]